all right
[Music]
mindful eating is the practice of being
fully present for a meal this may
involve slowing down the pace savoring
every bite and starting to get in tune
with your body's fullness cues when
you're distracted you tend to eat faster
and longer for example men and women
randomize to eat while watching TV
averaged an extra slice of pizza and 71
percent more mac and cheese totaling
nearly 300 additional calories that
alone could bump your weight like eight
pounds a year
this may help explain why one survey
found overweight individuals report they
ate nearly half their meals while
watching television
Stanford researchers found that on the
weekends about a quarter of kids
calories may be consumed in front of the
TV similarly study subjects told to eat
while giving their full attention to a
radio conversation or a detective story
recorded on cassette tapes like old
school podcast ended up eating
significantly more for instance up to 77
more ice cream compared to undestracted
eating even just engaging in
conversation even with friends can
inadvertently boost intake
distracted eating may also affect
subsequent consumption have people play
computer Solitaire while eating a fixed
calorie meal and they eat nearly twice
as many cookies a half hour later as if
they hadn't fully consciously registered
how much they ate when they were
distracted conversely if you have people
listen to an audio clip encouraging them
to eat mindfully focusing on the look
smell taste and texture of the food
hours later they eat fewer cookies than
those either eating in silence or
listening instead to some neutral
audiobook content attending to the
sensory qualities of food and our body's
reaction is just one aspect of mindful
eating mindfulness has been described as
a moment-to-moment awareness cultivated
by paying attention in a specific way in
the present moment as non-reactively
non-judgmentally and open-heartedly as
possible just being aware may not be
enough practicing mindfulness to deal
with Cravings is said to involve three
skills awareness the ability to monitor
one Cravings acceptance the ability to
refrain from judging yourself and then
something called disidentification or
cognitive diffusion the ability to
separate oneself from your cravings when
we're struck with a craving a typical
reaction is instead what's called
cognitive restructuring a psychological
term for challenging your thoughts and
replacing them with alternative thoughts
for example if you're hit with a thought
I need to eat some chocolate instead of
just reaching for a candy bar a
restructuring response might be no I
don't I can have something healthier
Instead This rarely works
more than a hundred self-identified
chocolate cravers were randomized to an
hour of cognitive restructuring
instruction and then given a bag of
chocolates to carry around with them for
a week to see how well they could resist
the temptation and they didn't do much
better than the control group that tried
it after no instruction at all
in contrast to cognitive restructuring
the mindful eating approach called
cognitive diffusion involves teaching
people to diffuse their thoughts as
merely thoughts placing mental distance
between themselves and their Cravings a
diffusion response to the thought I need
some chocolate would involve simply
observing the thought I notice I'm
having the thought that I need to eat
some chocolate and thinking one's mine
for the thought thanks mind
uh mind bus metaphor is used in which
people are taught to imagine themselves
as a driver of a bus and their thoughts
as mere passengers you visualize
yourself taking control and being like
thanks for the feedback folks but this
is my bus as you stop the bus and let
the negative passengers off
cognitive diffusion was tested head to
head against cognitive restructuring in
the same chocolate experiment and those
who got an hour of diffusion
instructions at three times greater odds
of remaining chocolate abstinent in the
face of a week of constant Temptation
then diffusion was put up against
acceptance instructing people to observe
a thought or feeling accept its presence
and build up a degree of tolerance for
uncomfortable feelings study subjects
were randomized to less than a half an
hour of coaching on diffusion acceptance
or a control group to spend the time
learning on muscle relaxation technique
they were then asked to carry a bag of
chocolate candy around for five days
untouched the acceptance group failed to
beat out the control group but the
diffusion group did of all the
mindfulness skills cognitive diffusion
appears to be the most effective a
simple and efficient approach to manage
food cravings
[Music]
thank you